{"name": "Z15 2019-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Given r = 4, b = 2, and g = -5, (r + b - g)( b + g) = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-33", "B": "-3 ", "C": "3", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Jeralyn purchases 1 box of granola bars and 6 boxes of chocolate bars for a total price of $22.00. The price of each box of granola bars is $2.50, and the price of each box of chocolate bars is n dollars. Which of the following equations models Jeralyn's purchase ?", "choices": {"A": "2.50 + 22.00 = 6n", "B": "2.50n + 22.00 = 6n", "C": "2.50(6n)  = 22.00", "D": "2.50 + 6n = 22.00", "E": "2.50n + 6n = 22.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. In \u0394ABC shown below, \u224c and the measure of \u2220A is 48\u00b0 . What is the measure of \u2220C?", "choices": {"A": "48\u00b0", "B": "84\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "96\u00b0", "E": "132\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. A square has a perimeter of 20 feet. What is the area, in square feet, of the square?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "10", "C": "25", "D": "40", "E": "80"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. A bag contains exactly 21 solid-colored buttons: 3 red, 6 blue, and 12 white. What is the probability of randomly selecting 1 button that is NOT white?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the value of |-7| - |7 - 29| ?", "choices": {"A": "-29", "B": "-15", "C": "15", "D": "29", "E": "43"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A store's revenue is the amount of money received for goods sold. A store's cost is the amount of money the store pays for the goods plus all the store's operating costs like rent, utilities, wages , etc. A store's net profit is the  difference  between  revenue  and  cost.  During 1 month, a grocery store paid $30,000 for goods that were sold for $39,500. With operating costs as shown below, what was the store's net profit for that month?", "choices": {"A": " $700", "B": " $800", "C": " $900", "D": "$1,000", "E": "$1,100"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. When Jorge began a driving trip, his car's odometer read 42 miles. After Jorge drove for 3 hours, the odometer read 165 miles . Which of the following values is closest to Jorge's average driving speed, in miles per hour, during those 3 hours?", "choices": {"A": "36", "B": "41", "C": "54", "D": "55", "E": "62"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Melinda and Jericho are painting a room in the city recreation center. They started with 5 gallons of paint. On the first day, Melinda used  gallon of paint and Jericho used  gallons of paint. How many gallons of paint were left after the first day?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. What value of x makes the equation below true?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "25", "E": "625"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. For functions  and , the value of  is:", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "10", "C": "70", "D": "970", "E": "1,030"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Tanisha, a manager at a state park, counted the money in the cash register at the end of her shift, and then she deposited the money in the bank. When she went back to her office, she accidentally shredded the  deposit slip. She remembered that there were only $5 and $ 10 bills. She also recalled that there were 27 bills totaling $205. How many $5 bills were in Tanisha's cash register at the end of her shift?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "14", "C": "16", "D": "23", "E": "32"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, a line intersects the y-axis at (0,2) and contains the point (8,3). What is the slope of the line? ", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. For   an  angle   with   measure  in   a  right triangle,  and . What is the value of ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The expression is equal to:", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "12", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. In  the   figure  below, XW intersects VZ at Y, the measure of \u2220XYV is (3x + 5)\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220ZYW is (4x - 6)\u00b0 . What is the measure of \u2220XYZ ?", "choices": {"A": "83\u00b0", "B": "97\u00b0", "C": "104\u00b0", "D": "142\u00b0", "E": "169\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. The table below shows the letter grades 60 students earned on the final exam in American Literature. The highest possible grade is A; the lowest possible grade is F.A student from this group will be chosen at random. What is the probability that the student's final exam grade is C or higher?", "choices": {"A": "0.3", "B": "0.4", "C": "0.6", "D": "0.7", "E": "0.9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. For  what  value  of   n   does   the   quadratic   equation x\u00b2 - 2x + n = 0 have solutions of x = 4 and x = -2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "-2", "C": "2", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. The circumference of a circle is 12\u03c0 inches. What is the area of the circle, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "4\u03c0", "B": "9\u03c0", "C": "12\u03c0", "D": "16\u03c0", "E": "36\u03c0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. The application for a license plate states that the license plate number has 3 letters followed by a 3-digit number, for example, AEE123. The letters O and I and the digit 0 cannot be part of the license plate number. Any of the other letters and digits may be  used up to 3 times. Which of the following expressions represents how many different license plate numbers are possible?", "choices": {"A": "24(23)(22)(9)(8)(7)", "B": "24(23)(22)(10)(10)(10)", "C": "24(24)(24)(9)(9)(9)", "D": "26(25)(24)(10)(9)(8)", "E": "26(26)(26)(10)(10)(10)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Which of the following expressions is equivalent  to 3(a + b) - 2(a - 5b) ?", "choices": {"A": "a - 9b", "B": "a - 7b", "C": "a - 4b", "D": "a + 8b", "E": "a + 13b"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In the figure  below, all of  the  small  squares  are equal in  area,  and  the  area  of  rectangle  ABCD  is  1  square unit. Which of the following expressions represents the area, in square units, of the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Marie is building a kite. In a drawing of her kite, shown below, AB = BC, AD = DC, the measure of \u2220ABC is 80\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220ADC is 50\u00b0\u3002What is the measure of \u2220BAD ?", "choices": {"A": "50\u00b0", "B": "65\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "115\u00b0", "E": "130\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The triangles below are similar (\u0394ABC ~ \u0394DEF). Which of the following is an expression for the area of \u0394ABC, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The interior of a rectangular shipping crate has dimensions 2 ft by 3 ft by 6 ft. The crate will be filled with cube-shaped boxes whose exteriors have dimensions 12 in by 12 in by 12 in. Given that no box can extend beyond the dimensions of the crate's interior, what is the maximum number of boxes the crate can hold?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "12", "C": "36", "D": "48", "E": "72"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "26. Use the following information to answer question 26-29.Shasta is participating in a bike ride for charity. The graph of speed (s) versus time (t) for the first 20 seconds of her bike ride is shown in the coordinate plane below. The graph is composed of 2 line segments for which the endpoints are at (0,0), (10,5), and (20,3). Shasta traveled 25 meters in the first 10 seconds.Beginning at t = 20 seconds, Shasta slows down as she approaches a familiar group of riders ahead of her and then travels at a constant speed with the group after joining them.26. What  is  Shasta's   speed,  in   metes  per  second,   at t = 3 seconds?", "choices": {"A": "1.5", "B": "2.0", "C": "2.5", "D": "3.0", "E": "6.0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer question 26-29.Shasta is participating in a bike ride for charity. The graph of speed (s) versus time (t) for the first 20 seconds of her bike ride is shown in the coordinate plane below. The graph is composed of 2 line segments for which the endpoints are at (0,0), (10,5), and (20,3). Shasta traveled 25 meters in the first 10 seconds.Beginning at t = 20 seconds, Shasta slows down as she approaches a familiar group of riders ahead of her and then travels at a constant speed with the group after joining them.27.  Shasta's  acceleration,    a,    over   the   interval   from t = 10 seconds to t = 20 seconds, is equal to the slope of the graph over that interval, measured in meters per second per second. What is the value of a?", "choices": {"A": " -5", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": "2", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer question 26-29.Shasta is participating in a bike ride for charity. The graph of speed (s) versus time (t) for the first 20 seconds of her bike ride is shown in the coordinate plane below. The graph is composed of 2 line segments for which the endpoints are at (0,0), (10,5), and (20,3). Shasta traveled 25 meters in the first 10 seconds.Beginning at t = 20 seconds, Shasta slows down as she approaches a familiar group of riders ahead of her and then travels at a constant speed with the group after joining them.28. Calen started  his bike ride earlier  than  Shasta. During the first 15 seconds of Shasta's ride, Calen  was  traveling at a constant speed equal to  of Shasta' s maximum speed during that same time period. How far, in meters, did Calen travel during the first 15 seconds of Shasta's ride?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "25", "C": "", "D": "45", "E": "75"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer question 26-29.Shasta is participating in a bike ride for charity. The graph of speed (s) versus time (t) for the first 20 seconds of her bike ride is shown in the coordinate plane below. The graph is composed of 2 line segments for which the endpoints are at (0,0), (10,5), and (20,3). Shasta traveled 25 meters in the first 10 seconds.Beginning at t = 20 seconds, Shasta slows down as she approaches a familiar group of riders ahead of her and then travels at a constant speed with the group after joining them.29. Which of the following graphs best represents the portion of Shasta's ride beginning at t=20 seconds?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The lengths of 2 adjacent sides of a rectangle are represented by x + 2 feet and 2x + 7 feet. In terms of x, what is the area, in square feet, of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "6x + 18", "B": "2x\u00b2 + 14", "C": "2x\u00b2 + 9x + 14", "D": "2x\u00b2 + 11x + 9", "E": "2x\u00b2 + 11x + 14"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Which one of the following inequalities is true?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Two fair coins are repeatedly tossed simultaneously. What is the probability that both coins land heads up on the 36th toss?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Suppose a student's course grade is determined solely by that student's scores on 8 tests, which are worth 100 points each. If Bane has an average of exactly 88 points on the first 6 tests, how many points must he average on the last 2 tests to earn exactly a 90-point course grade?", "choices": {"A": "99", "B": "96", "C": "95", "D": "94", "E": "92"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Which of the following operations will produce the largest result when substituted for the blank in theexpression 62 ______", "choices": {"A": "Averaged with", "B": "Divided by", "C": "Minus", "D": "Plus", "E": "Multiplied by"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Given the sets A = {0, 1, 2, 3} and B = {1, 3, 5, 7}, which of the following defines a function f from A onto B ?", "choices": {"A": "f(x) = 2x + 1", "B": "f(x) = 2x - 1", "C": "f(x) = 3x - 1", "D": "f(x) = 3x - 2", "E": "f(x) = x + 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. If , , and , which of the following orders x, y, and z from least to greatest?", "choices": {"A": "x &lt; y &lt; z", "B": "y &lt; x &lt; z", "C": "y &lt; z &lt; x", "D": "z &lt; x &lt; y", "E": "z &lt; y &lt; x"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Isosceles triangle \u0394ABC has an altitude of h inches, a base of 36 inches, and 2 base angles measuring 76\u00b0 each, as shown in the figure below. What is the value of h?", "choices": {"A": "18 sin76\u00b0", "B": "18 tan76\u00b0", "C": "36 cot76\u00b0", "D": "36 sin76\u00b0", "E": "36  tan76\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The least common multiple (LCM) of 2 numbers is 216. The larger of the 2 numbers is 108. What is the greatest value the other number can have?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "36", "D": "54", "E": "72"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In the standard (x,y) coordinate  plane,  given Parabola A with equation y = 3x\u00b2, Parabola B is the image of Parabola A after a shift of 7 coordinate units to the left and 4 coordinate units down. Parabola B has which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": "y = 3(x - 4)\u00b2 - 7", "B": "y = 3(x - 7)\u00b2 - 4", "C": "y = 3(x - 7)\u00b2 + 4", "D": "y = 3(x + 7)\u00b2 - 4", "E": "y = 3(x + 7)\u00b2 + 4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "41. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.In 2012, pollsters for the Gallup Organization asked a random sample of 1,014 adults, \"On the average, about how much does your family spend on food each week?\" The table below lists the percent of the sample that gave each response. For example, approximately 21% of adults in the sample responded that, on average, they spend no less than $200 but no more than $299 on food each week.41.  Which of the following expressions is equal to the approximate number of adults from the sample that said they spend an average of less than $100 each week on food?", "choices": {"A": "1,014(22)", "B": "1,014(25)", "C": "1,014(47)", "D": "1,014(0.22)", "E": "1,014(0.25)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.In 2012, pollsters for the Gallup Organization asked a random sample of 1,014 adults, \"On the average, about how much does your family spend on food each week?\" The table below lists the percent of the sample that gave each response. For example, approximately 21% of adults in the sample responded that, on average, they spend no less than $200 but no more than $299 on food each week.42.  What percent of adults in the sample responded that they spend, on average, at least $150 each week on food?", "choices": {"A": "15%", "B": "46%", "C": "49%", "D": "51%", "E": "66%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer question 41-43.In 2012, pollsters for the Gallup Organization asked a random sample of 1,014 adults, \"On the average, about how much does your family spend on food each week?\" The table below lists the percent of the sample that gave each response. For example, approximately 21% of adults in the sample responded that, on average, they spend no less than $200 but no more than $299 on food each week.43.  A pollster will create a circle graph using the information in the table. One sector of the circle graph will represent the percent of adults in the sample who said they spend an average of $300 or more on food each week. What will be the measure of the central angle for that sector?", "choices": {"A": "10\u00b0", "B": "13\u00b0", "C": "36\u00b0", "D": "45\u00b0", "E": "47\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. A spherical droplet of ink strikes a vertical wall, as modeled in the figure below. The angle of impact is indicated by \u03b8 in the figure.The stain the droplet leaves on the wall is oval-shaped.  Scientists can measure the maximum length and maximum width of the stain to determine the angle of impact according to the formula :The figure below models such a stain. What was the impact angle of the droplet that left this stain?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "45\u00b0", "C": "60\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0", "E": "120\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The graph below shows the distribution of a data set consisting of 16 positive integers. Which of the following statements about the mean, median, and mode of the data set is true?", "choices": {"A": "The mode is less than the median, and the median is less than the mean.", "B": "The mode is less than the mean, and the mean is equal to the median.", "C": "The mode is equal to the mean, and the mean is less than the median.", "D": "The mean is  less than  the median, and the median is less than the mode.", "E": "The mean is equal to the median, and the median is equal to the mode."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Yolanda collects trading cards, and she has started her younger brothers, Xavier and Zach, collecting cards as well. As of today, Zach owns 5 more cards than Xavier, and Yolanda owns twice as many cards as Xavier and Zach combined. Which of the following equations expresses the relationship between y, the number of cards Yolanda owns, and x, the number of cards Xavier owns?", "choices": {"A": "y = x - 5", "B": "y = x + 5", "C": "y = 2x", "D": "y = 4x - 10", "E": "y = 4x + 10"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. What is the distance, in coordinate units, between the points (-2,1) and (1, 10) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": "12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. A rectangular solid has a volume of 100 cubic units. If the length, width, and height of the solid are each doubled, what will the volume, in cubic units, of the new solid be?", "choices": {"A": "200", "B": "400", "C": "600", "D": "800", "E": "2,700"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The set of all values of x that satisfies  |x - 2| &lt; 7  is the same as the set of all values of x that satisfies:", "choices": {"A": "0 &lt; x &lt; 5", "B": "0 &lt; x &lt; 9", "C": "-5 &lt; x &lt; 5", "D": "-5 &lt; x &lt; 9", "E": "-9 &lt; x &lt; 9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The fifth power of a number is 380,204,032. The number is between:", "choices": {"A": "1 and 10", "B": "10 and 100", "C": "100 and 1,000", "D": "1,000 and 100,000", "E": "100,000 and 100,000,000"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Given A = , B = , and C = , if it is possible to calculate C + AB, which of the following matrices is the result?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "It is not possible to calculate C + AB"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Given 0 \u2264 x \u2264 8 and y \u2265 18, what is the greatest value of  can be determined?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The graph below gives the speed, in knots (nautical miles per hour), of a cruise ship during a  5-hour period. Which of the following values is closest to the rate of change, in knots per hour, of the speed of the ship between hours 2 and 4 ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "10", "E": "25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. A fair spinner with 4  equally  sized  regions  and  an arrow has regions numbered 1, 2, 3, and 4, respectively, and a second fair spinner with 5 equally sized regions, and an arrow has regions numbered 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5, respectively. The arrows are both spun at the same time, and the numbers the 2 arrows land on are multiplied together. What is the probability that this product is  an odd number?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The bottom of a swimming pool, shown below, has an area of 630 square feet and a perimeter of 114 ft. The swimming pool has a uniform depth of 5 ft of water, and the given lengths are in feet. If it can  be determined , what is the volume of water, in cubic feet, that the pool contains?", "choices": {"A": "3,150", "B": "3,335", "C": "3,520", "D": "3,720", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. For all positive integers a and b, the expression(a!)b is equivalent to one of the following expressions. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "(a)b!", "B": "(ab)!", "C": "b(a!)", "D": "ab(-1 + -2 + -3 + \u2026 )", "E": "[a(a-1)(a-2)\u2026(1)]b"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The standard normal probability  distribution  function (\u00b5= 0 and \u03c3 = 1) is graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Which of the following percentages is closest to the percent of the data  points that are within 2 standard deviations  of  the  mean  in any normal distribution?", "choices": {"A": "50%", "B": "68%", "C": "90%", "D": "95%", "E": "99%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For what value of b will the determinant of the matrix have a value of 18?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "-3", "C": "3", "D": "6", "E": "15"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. What are the solutions to  x\u00b2- 2x + 17 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "-3 and 5", "B": " ", "C": "1 \u00b1 4i", "D": "1 \u00b1 8i", "E": "2 \u00b1 8i"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Shown below are the top, front, and right side views of a stack of 1-centimeter cubes. The labels T, F, and R specify where the top, front, and right side s are located with respect to the view. What is the volume , in cubic centimeters, of the stack of cubes?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "8", "C": "9", "D": "12", "E": "14"}, "correct": "B"}]}